https://opentuition.com/cookie-policy/

Skip to primary navigation Skip to main content Skip to primary sidebarIssues with the ACCA remote exams >>
& Official ACCA response >>LatestACCAAsk ACCA TutorOBUCIMAAsk CIMA TutorFIABuy/SellQualifiedForum RulesFor more information about the use of cookies while visiting our sites, please email admin@opentuition.com.What is a cookie?A cookie is a small file that can be placed on your device that allows us to recognise and remember you. It is sent to your browser and stored on your computer’s hard drive or tablet or mobile device. When you visit our sites, we may collect information from you automatically through cookies or similar technology.How do we use cookies?We use cookies in a range of ways to improve your experience on our site, includingKeeping you signed inUnderstanding how you use our siteWorking with partners to serve you relevant advertising.Other organisations also collect user information on our sites through cookies, tags and pixels. Tags and pixels, also known as web beacons, are similar to cookies but are collected through embedded images.Using cookies and other technology allows other organisations to help us to analyse how our site is being used, measure the number of visitors to the site, and display advertising.Cookies that are used by the OpenTuition are referred to as “first-party cookies” and those that are used by our partners are “third-party cookies”. Because of how cookies work, our website cannot access third-party cookies; nor can other organisations access the data in the cookies we use on our website. There are more details about both in the following sections.What types of cookies do we use ?We use three types of cookies, which we describe in this section.Essential – cookies that are essential to provide you with services you have requested. For example, these include the cookies that make it possible for you to stay logged into your OpenTuition account and make comments. If you set your browser to block these cookies, then these functions and services will not work for you. In particular, we won’t be able to save your preferences about cookies.Performance – cookies which measure how often you visit our sites and how you use them. For example, we collect information about which of our pages are most frequently visited, and by which types of users. We also use third-party cookies to help with performance. For example, the Google Analytics cookie gives us information such as your journey between pages and whether you have downloaded anything.Advertising – cookies that are used to collect information about your visit to our site, the content you have viewed, the links you have followed and information about your browser, device and your IP address. We have set out more details on this below.How do we use cookies for advertising?Cookies are a key part of how we deliver advertising on our sites. Among other uses, they allow us to show more relevant advertising to people who visit opentuition.com by showing you adverts that are based on your browsing patterns and the way you have interacted with our sites and apps. We can then show you adverts which we believe may interest you.As you browse our site, some of the cookies and similar technology we place on your device are for advertising, so we can understand what sorts of pages you read and are interested in. We can then display advertising on your browser based on these interests. For instance, if you have been reading a lot of food and drink articles, you may be shown more adverts for food and drink.The advertising techniques we use do not collect information such as your name, email address, postal address or phone number. We sometimes use information such as your IP address and browser type and also sometimes share some limited aspects of this with third parties for advertising purposes.There are times when we want to reach OpenTuition student who use social media to market our own products and services, we use cookies to help with this. For example, we place a pixel on our web pages that allows Facebook to place cookies on web browsers. When a OpenTuition user who uses Facebook returns to Facebook, Facebook can identify them as part of a group of OpenTuition readers and on behalf of the OpenTuition they can serve them with marketing messages from us. The data that can be obtained from a visit to the OpenTuition is limited to the URL of the pages that have been visited and, in some cases, the status of any unfinished or completed commercial transactions undertaken with us, together with the limited information a browser might pass on, such as its IP address. If you are a Facebook user you can opt out by following the link below.We may also share online data collected through cookies and similar technology with our advertising partners. This means that when you are on another website, you may be shown advertising based on your browsing patterns on theguardian.com. We may also show you advertising on opentuition.com website based on your browsing patterns on other sites that we have obtained from our advertising partners.Online retargeting is another form of online advertising that allows us and some of our advertising partners to show you advertising based on your browsing patterns and interactions with other sites. The use of cookies may mean that when you are on another site, you may be shown advertising based on what you have looked at on opentuition.com.For example, if you have visited the website of an online clothes shop, you may start seeing adverts from that same shopping site displaying special offers or showing you the products you were browsing. This allows companies to advertise to you if you leave their website without making a purchase.How to manage advertising cookiesYou can manage the use of cookies, including advertising cookies, and disable the sharing of data with partners for advertising purposes by using the steps set out here. In some cases you can turn off advertising cookies on a cookie-by-cookie basis, and we give the most common examples below.You can find information about how to opt out of the cookies provided by our key partners here:Facebook pixelAdvertising cookieOpt outPrivacy policyGoogle AdwordsAdvertising cookieOpt outPrivacy policyGoogle AdxAdvertising cookieOpt outPrivacy policyGoogle AnalyticsPerformance cookieOpt outPrivacy policyGoogle DoubleClickAdvertising cookieOpt outPrivacy policyTwitterAdvertising cookieOpt outPrivacy policyYou can further manage the use of advertising cookies and disable the sharing of data with partners for advertising purposes. This option will reduce the number of advertising partners with whom we share your data, although you will still see some advertising that has been tailored to you as well as advertising intended for OpenTuition readers in general. You can switch some cookies off through the Your Online Choices site. You may need to do this again each time you use a different IP address or device.It is also possible to stop your browser from accepting cookies altogether by changing your browser’s cookie settings. You can usually find these settings in the “options” or “preferences” menu of your browser. The following links may be helpful, or you can use the “Help” option in your browser.Cookie settings in Internet ExplorerCookie settings in FirefoxCookie settings in ChromeCookie settings in Safari web and iOSUseful linksIf you would like to find out more about privacy, cookies and their use on the internet, you may find the following links useful:Microsoft cookies guideAll About CookiesThe Information Commissioner’s Office  Primary SidebarDonateDonateIf you have benefited from our materials please donateDonate nowYou can also “donate your time” and help out other students on the Students Forums
